breaking reetus has literally made me a
millionaire like I am not even kidding
an actual millionaire breing reetus made
me
$26,000 in 12 hours and in this video
I'm going to show you how you can use
break and retest to your advantage and
have an edge on the market which break
and retest is one of the most common
patterns in the whole entire Market
that's why it's made me so much money
and a lot of people they try and figure
it out but they simply don't get it and
that's what this video is about I'm
going to teach you how to properly use
break and retest oh and keep in mind if
you really understand and you compreh
the break and retest strategy you
literally don't have to worry about
anything else cuz breaking retest
happens literally every single day in
the market and it's so easy to
comprehend because it's that simple it's
literally what it is break and retest
you're going to see it every single day
in the market but it's almost so simple
that a lot of people they over
complicate it they try to see it further
than a break and retest there's just
simple it's a break and retest and
that's it so it's simple don't overthink
it but I'm going to make it clear in
this video so let's get into it but
before getting into the actual charts
let me show you what this pattern looks
like and it's this right here looks
simple right looks like a break and
retest looks like price is breaking
retesting and then heading to the upside
obviously if you flip it around price is
in Breaking retest and then heading to
the downside well that's pretty much it
like I just said it's something very
simple and it happens every single day
in the market it can happen across all
different time frames and it can happen
across all different currency pairs all
different Commodities Futures stocks
anything because it's a break and retest
the market has to move up and down and
as it's moving up and down it leaves
this pattern known as break and retest
and what price wants to communicate to
you with a break and retest is a
continuation breaking retest is a
continuation pattern but price just
can't continuously go up forever it has
to have 1 second to then pause have a
small retracement to then continue
heading to the upside it's almost like
if you're in the gym and you want to hit
multiple reps in your set in order for
you to hit that next rep you have to
take a breath you have to take a break
for about a second or two and then you
can go ahead and hit it again it's the
same thing here with with the market
just the market obviously doesn't stop
and breathe the market is always moving
but the retracement of the market coming
back and retesting is its form of
breathing so that it can have the next
push and it could push the next rep to
the market continue in the direction
that it was originally headed to D do
and breaking retest kind of works
everywhere but not really it works best
at a strong area whether it's a support
and resistance supply and demand area of
interest it's all the same thing it's a
price where once price breaks price can
use that retracement at a point for it
to hold on for about a second or two and
then it continue heading to the upside
or continue heading to the downside now
breaking retest is most effective at
these zones and these zones are
obviously known as support and
resistance supply and demand area of
interest it's all the same thing it's a
resting point for price to then create
accumulation to then push to then to the
next zone so now let's actually get into
the market so I can show you some very
clear examples of how breaking ret works
so as you guys can see right here this
to some of you guys might look like a
very messy chart or obviously a chart
that goes to the upside but you can't
really see it clear but little do you
know there is about five to six
different examples of a very clear
breaking retest that happens here
continuously now this chart we are on
the daily time frame and I want you to
keep in mind breaking retest happens on
every single time frame it could happen
on the daily the weekly the one minute 2
minute doesn't matter but keep a note
that the higher the time frame the more
it is going to be respected so if you
have a break and retest on The Daily
it's going to be much more respected and
a break retest on the 5 minute I
personally like using my break and
retest on The 4our Daily to continuation
trades and then for entries on the lower
time frames but all of that is going to
make sense right now so as you guys can
see right here GBP nzd this is a prime
example of a trend continuation break
and then retest and the way you mark up
break and retest is simply by using this
little box right here now doesn't matter
the size of the box it can be this big
can be this big as long as you kind of
get enough room so you can get the
multiple Taps into it so a perfect
example of a first break and retest is
this zone right here for it to be a
valid level of a break and retest you
need to have a minimum of one structure
point for price to literally be able to
then break the zone and then come back
and then retest it so as you can tell
right here this is the level of
resistance price has then broken it and
then we have then retested it so this is
a perfect example of a break and retest
now that we have broken this Zone and we
have retested it this right here turns
into the next structure point that we
can then have the break and retest so as
you can see right here I get my trusty
Zone and now this is the resistance
level we Break It We retest it and then
we have a simple continuation remember
breaking retest is a continuation
pattern it so price has a break in the
retest it has a breathing room it's able
to now get ready to then continue
heading in that direction that's exactly
what we're seeing here next we have our
next Zone Z which is the next high point
which is this point right here mark it
off as a Zone and you can see how price
clearly breaks and then retest it and
this goes on and on and on and then you
can also see how it does it to now the
downside so as you can see here this was
marked off as a high point but then
price was never able to then retest this
structure point right here this would
have been an ideal break retest to then
head to the upside but this is a perfect
example of what didn't happen which you
didn't get any entry signal you didn't
get an engulfing Candlestick and all
that stuff you want to know more about
bullish engulfing bearish engulfing and
how you can use that effectively with
break and retest just look at this video
right here it's going to explain to you
how to properly use an engulfing
Candlestick with Trend continuation but
with that being said this right here
would have been an ideal break and
retest but you didn't get that engulfing
candles state that I'm talking about so
then price completely broke under and
then what did we do we broke and then
retested the next structure point which
is this point point right here and we
can just simply keep this going with
every single structure point that the
market presents us with for example this
next low right here we have simply then
broke and then retested it and continue
heading to the downside this very clear
it's simple it's just a step price has
to have a high have to have a
retracement so continue having a high
and then if we're heading to the
downside price has to have a low and has
to have a lower high so then we continue
heading to the down it's a very simple
pattern and ideally to use it for your
day Trad you want to use it more on the
4our one hour depending on how approach
you want to take it for your Inay and
swing trades you want to take it on the
daily and then weekly time frame keep in
mind the higher the time frame the more
respected the break and retest is going
to be so now that you understand what a
break and retest looks like let's
actually see how you can enter the trade
put a stop loss and a take profit so the
break and retest is to identify Trend
continuation but now the actual entry
signal you have to go on the lower time
frame so for this example right here
we're just going to Zone this off right
I'm just picking random Parts in the
chart I didn't even pre-record this or
pre-notice the zones I just popped it up
I literally have this zone right here so
we're just going to see all of these
breaks and retests and see how we could
have gotone in in every single one of
these trades so for example let's just
go down to the 4 Hour so if we scroll
left we can see this example right here
so this is a perfect example right here
of our first break and retest which is
this trade right here as you can see
price has then broken this zone so then
this is the area where we are expecting
price to then come back and then retest
and as we're having the retest in order
for us to take a trade trade we need to
have a bullish engulfing Candlestick
confirmation so if you see right here we
have the retracement we're rejecting the
previous structure level we're having
the break and now we're having the
retest so here you can see we're clearly
having the break and now we're having
the retest but how do you know the
retest is done how do you know that this
is the area where you're now going to
reject from and now have a higher high
move well very simple because you have
rejection candlesticks and it does not
get more clear than what you're seeing
right here which is actually a series of
bullish engulfing Morning Star formation
which you have three dogee Candlestick
rejections one bullish engulfing you
would have simply put your entry point
right here and then you would have put
your stop loss right under this point
and then your take profit would have
been based off of a minimum of a 1 to
two risk to reward simple look at that
how it hits the take profit perfectly
does not get any more simple than that
but if that's not enough we'll continue
on to our next trade which would be this
point right here which this is the high
so now we have next break and then after
the next break we then have our retest
which would be this point right here and
then we would enter our trade after this
bullish engulfing we would have our
entry point right there and our stop
loss point would be right here if we
were to have a one to2 rward ratio we
simply just scroll this to the right
this example we would have simply been
Wicked out simply because the market had
fluctuation it is what it is it happens
but we keep it going we don't stop so
then the next break and retest what
happened at this point right here price
then breaks retest on this break and
retest right here you have that morning
star formation bullish engulf and
Candlestick it's literally the same
thing every single time your stop- loss
is right under it you have a minimum of
a 1 to two risk to reward and then this
trade hit so if you notice out of the
three trades you had one that you caught
a minimum of a 1 to two so you let save
you risk 1% you got 2% on this trade you
lost 1% on this trade so now you're down
1% % but now plus 2% you're a net profit
over 3% on these three trades that could
have happened in the matter of 48 Hours
you multiply 3% in 48 hours and it say
you only take that once a week you
multiply that 3% that you made in one
week times 4 weeks than you have in the
market you can average anywhere from 9
to 12% a month that's more than any
single Bank any single institution with
a simple break and retest strategy
there's nothing that I'm doing different
other than just break and retest and
bullish and golfing Candlestick and
everything I've showed you in this video
is an example of what I do with my set
freet strategy it's something that I've
been using for the last 5 and a half
years and it's clearly making me money
every single day I actually want to see
how I am in the trade right now as of
right now in the trade we are currently
about
$37,000 in profit and you guys can see
it happening right there live right now
and these aren't my only numbers
students that use my set forget strategy
make anywhere from ,000 to $1,500 a week
as a beginner set and forget Trader now
if you're probably wondering what is set
and forget and how you can use it and
make numbers like these just click the
link in the description below there's a
video that explains to you exactly what
set and forget is and how it makes
traders in the first 3 months of using
set and forget to make anywhere from
,000 to $1,500 a week as a beginner set
and forget Trader so you want to know
more about set and forget and how you
can use it every single day along with
the breaking retest strategy so you can
use a set and fra in combination with it
all and make numbers like these just
click the link in the description below
I have a video there for you that's
going to explain absolutely everything
and I hope you guys found this video
useful appreciate you guys watching this
video all the way to the end and I'll
see you guys in the next video